<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self on kshitij10496</title>
    <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/categories/self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self on kshitij10496</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 21:14:45 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kshitij10496.github.io/categories/self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Education</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/on-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 21:14:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/on-education/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about education.
There are 2 complementary aspects of getting an education:
 the scholarly education obtained from rigorously studying academic texts obtained from schooling.
 the practical education learned from life experiences dealing in the real world.
  I&amp;rsquo;m sure that most of us would agree that they fall somewhere on this spectrum of the wise and academic to the streetwise and practical.
Too much theory results in losing Skin in The Game while too much of hacking renders the bigger picture of your life a blur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List 2019</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/reading-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 16:56:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/reading-2019/</guid>
      <description>Heading into 2019, I aim to read a lot of books across genres - from historical fictions to the latest genetics developments, from philosophy about human societies to the realities of individual emotions.
Over the weekend, I updated my Goodreads shelves and downloaded a lot of &amp;ldquo;Samples&amp;rdquo; on my Kindle from the Amazon Store. My intention is to read these preview chapters at random on my Kindle and dive into only those books which interest me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Write Go</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/on-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 09:06:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/on-go/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: This is not a rant about how Go is &amp;ldquo;superior&amp;rdquo; to other languages. It&amp;rsquo;s all apples and oranges and I like them both, not at the same time, ofcourse! 🍎/🍊
off-topic: When I was a little boy 👦, I used to play all day long with my legos - constructing buildings, trucks, everything that I could imagine. Chaining dominoes with my parent&amp;rsquo;s music collection cassettes, solving jigsaw puzzles and playing scrabble with my cousins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Blog Great Again</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:21:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/blogging/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: post about posting more posts
I have forgotten to write blog posts for over a year or have I?
Blogging 101 I started this blog after I was selected as a GSoC 2016 student under SymPy so as to log my progress. Few weeks working into the program, it seemed that I had developed the habit of writing weekly articles. Back then, I intended to continue maintaining my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>