<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>essay on kxsh</title>
    <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/tags/essay/</link>
    <description>Recent content in essay on kxsh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 21:33:32 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kshitij10496.github.io/tags/essay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetry</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/on-asymmetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 21:33:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/on-asymmetry/</guid>
      <description>cross-posting from 200 Words A Day
Let’s talk about the asymmetries in our lives today.
After reading Fooled By Randomness and The Black Swan from Nassim Nicholas Taleb, I am convinced by the presence and importance of asymmetries in all walks of our lives. Moreover, these asymmetries are almost always associated with a “rare”(low probability), “unforeseeable”, highly consequential event (called a Black Swan).
Turning a blind eye to them can result in a massive blowup – the much fraught unbecoming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/on-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 21:37:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/on-education/</guid>
      <description>cross-posting from 200 Words A Day
Let’s talk about education today.
There are 2 complementary aspects of getting an education:
the scholarly education obtained from rigorously studying academic texts obtained from schooling. the practical education learned from life experiences dealing in the real world. I’m sure that most of us would agree that they fall somewhere on this spectrum of the wise and academic to the streetwise and practical.
Too much theory results in losing Skin in The Game while too much of hacking renders the bigger picture of your life a blur.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
