<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gsoc on kshitij10496</title>
    <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/categories/gsoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gsoc on kshitij10496</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kshitij10496.github.io/categories/gsoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 10 &amp; 11 - The One with `solvify`</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-10-11/</guid>
      <description>FiniteSet | list
ImageSet, | list (if `f` is periodic) Union | EmptySet | empty list Others | None  Adding domain support.
I added a domain argument to isolve whose default value is the real domain (domain=S.Reals). A few limitation to the conditions of S.Infinity and S.NegativeInfinity followed.
Another noticable point, from the point of implementation, was to deal with singularities and discontinuities of the given inequality. For this, I used the continuous_domain method to find the continuous domains of the expression within the specified domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 09 - The One with Inequalities</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-09/</guid>
      <description>This week I worked on solving trigonometric inequalities.
Trigonometric inequalities The primary univariate inequality solver - solve_univariate_inequality,
depends upon the results of solve in order to solve the given inequality. Taking a cue from PR#10022 on incorporating solveset for inequalities, I worked on developing an approach for replacing the use of solve with solveset in solving inequalities.
Idea
 Convert Set-type output from solveset to list objects similar to that returned by solve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 07 - The One With Generalised Periodicity</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-07/</guid>
      <description>This week I updated my PR#11277 to find the period of a general function.
Periodicity In the past few weeks, I dedicated a lot of my time reading about the property of periodicity of a function. Earlier, I had implemented a trivial(and restricted) functionality for this task. This motivated me to study this topic as I planned to generalise the function.
Here are my notes on periodicity which were the literature reference for the development of the method:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 06 - The One with Singularities</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-06/</guid>
      <description>This week I worked on the topic of singularities.
Singularities  A singularity is in general a point at which a given mathematical object is not defined.
 Examples:
 1/x has a singularity at x = 0 as it seems to reach infinity. |x| (Absolute) has a singularity at x = 0 since it is not differentiable at that point. √x (Square root) has a singularity at x = 0 since it doesnot admit a tangent there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Weeks 04 &amp; 05 - The One with Periodicity</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-04-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-04-05/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks !
The past couple of weeks were spent of developing heuristics for determining the fundamental period of a given trigonometric function.
In our higher school, we all must have come across Trigonometric Functions. One of the most striking properties of these functions is their periodicty.
The ability of a function to repeat its values in regular intervals has always caught my imagination.
Motivation Well, SymPy ought to have a functionality to determine the period of a function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 03 - The One With Function Range (Part II)</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-03/</guid>
      <description>Hey !
This week I worked on implementing a method for finding the range of a function in a given domain. Following from last weeek&amp;rsquo;s research on the same, I tried to develop these utility functions.
Implementation Here, I have defined the two functions along with some of their implementation details:
continuous_in(f, x, interval)
The function returns the sub-domains as an Union of Interval in case a discontinuity exists in the interval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 02 - The One With Function Range (Part I)</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-02/</guid>
      <description>This week I worked on developing methods for computing the range of an univariate function. For this pupose, I spent most of my time in research; reading previous discussions on mailing lists, pull requests and wikis.
Progress Suppose, we want to solve the following equation in the variable x:
sin(x) = π / 2
We can straight away state that this equations has no solutions as the range of the function sin is -1 to 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 01 - The One with Intersections</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/gsoc-week-01/</guid>
      <description>$ git log PR #11149 : Intersection of null Range and an Interval returns EmptySet
PR #11164 : Intersection of certain ImageSets with Intervals
In the next week, I will try to design a method to determine the range of a function in the given domain.
This will require some digging up and a bit of research.
Looking forward to it !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving equations via Decomposition and Rewriting</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/solving-equations-via-decomposition-and-rewriting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/solving-equations-via-decomposition-and-rewriting/</guid>
      <description>A robust framework for solving equations is a salient feature of any Computer Algebra System. An important idea in this regard is &amp;ldquo;Rewriting and Decomposition&amp;rdquo;. By using this techniques, we try to reduce the given equation to a set of simpler equations which can be solved with relative ease.
An example here would be the best way to establish the significance of the above idea.
If we have to solve for x in the equation f(x) = 0, where</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auditing SymPy&#39;s Transcendental solver</title>
      <link>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/auditing-transcendental-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kshitij10496.github.io/posts/auditing-transcendental-solver/</guid>
      <description>Having considered the current codebase of _tsolve function, I find the following few points considered while implementing the new solver:
 modularise the code for various classes of equations(LambertW, bivariate equation type, logarithmic, exponential).
 using SymPy Set objects internally, instead of using the built-in Python lists.
 use of decompogen function to check for possible decomposition of the given expression into simpler functions. handle the case where the given equation has no closed-form solution and infinite recursion occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>